Hello! Welcome to another video on
Bug Bounty Reports Explained channel!
This time it's a new series called Bounty Vlog.
What is it about?
Well, something I don't like about social media
is that it can make all of us feel worthless.
Chances are that if you open Twitter feed right now,
you will see tweets like "I earned
X amount of dollars
today" or "I reported 3 criticas in 2 hours" or something like that.
I do this sometimes myself,
but I generally don't like it, and I know it doesn't help anyone.
On the other hand, I see people like Shubs
who show us all their journey, and I hugely, hugely respect it.
And I would like to do something similar or maybe even better, because
I would like to show you my journey from the beginning - from right now.
How much time I spend?
How many vulnerabilities I find?
How different methodologies and programs work for me?
I think this will be especially valuable a few years from now
after I gain a lot of experience and I become successful.
Today is the 0th episode where I will show you what my background
was, my I.T.
security journey so far and how I was able to leave my pentesting job
with such a small YouTube channel.
Enjoy!
I started my I.T.
security journey quite late - just before going to university.
First, I found out about CTFs and they were absolutely awesome for me.
Then, I found out there is a profession called pentester, and back then
I thought it just like CTFs, except you're getting paid for it.
But back then, I didn't know how hard it is to get to the field.
I thought that I would need a few years of university,
then a few years of programing experience,
and only then I could aspire to be a pentester. But I was wrong.
After a year of university, along with learning security
in my free time, I got a job as a pentester on my second year.
It was a dream, but I never felt that I'm good enough to stop learning.
I'm generally a learning junkie.
I want to optimize and learn everything from IT security tools, through
time organization to even such simple things like peeling an orange.
I just want to do it as well as I can.
And bug bounty seems like a perfect fit for me
because here, unless you are doing a lot of recon,
you won't find a simple XSS in the commonly used parameter.
There are a lot of good write ups, and I learn a ton reading them.
And that's how Bug Bounty Reports Explained channel was born.
Originally,
I just did it to document my learning journey and have a personal brand
to maybe start doing it
more seriously a few years from now after I'm bored doing pentests.
But fast forward one and a half year, and I'm kinda doing it
full time now.
I didn't want to continue doing both those things simultaneously
because they just take too much time.
Instead, I decided that I am in a position to quit my job,
even though I was making pretty much no money from YouTube.
It was just more interesting to me
and I didn't have a specific plan - I just wanted to see what happens
when I invest more time into this and into bug bounty.
Do I make more money now than I did as a pentester? Definitely not.
But when quitting my job,
I had about a year worth of savings on my account, and right now
I'm in a very comfortable position
where I don't need to make money because I live off of my savings.
Everything I make through bounties, BBRE
Premium or sponsorship deals is a kind of bonus to me.
Right now, I focus on learning and growing,
and I hope that money will follow.
And actually, it seems like they do
because it's been four months and instead of burning my savings,
I'm actually month-to-month extending them.
Apart from my bounties, I'd like to thank BBRE Premium subscribers and
companies like the Detectify who sponsor the content on this channel.
It's also awesome to be my own boss and I have much more free time now.
Even if in some time I decide that I want to go back
to just being employed and getting a stable salary month to month,
I will be happy to have taken this risk and experience
what I'm experiencing right now.
The reason I created the
channel and the newsletter is the lack of good quality content
that is not for beginners.
Even though some marketing gurus think I'm making a mistake
because beginners are always the biggest audience.
And I agree that with doing a web security course for beginners,
I may have better financial results.
What I am doing right now is just much more interesting to me,
and this is the most important thing.
The same goes for BBRE Premium.
You can learn web security with me there
if you are not interested in totally beginner content. Every two weeks,
I send an email with tons of hacking tips and tool tutorials.
I also don't have a Patreon or Buy Me A Coffee,
so that's the only way to support me right now.
I am not that good at marketing,
so there aren't hundreds of people there.
But the most important thing is that
those that are there are very happy with it.
What is the bug bounty in all that you might ask?
Since day one, I learned about them, It was very appealing to me.
Working from any location in the world,
being able to self manage my time and finally,
being awarded based on the performance and not on time
put is something that I want to do.
Especially that I strongly believe
that if I put the time into this , I will succeed.
But I made a lot of mistakes.
At the beginning,
I just didn't have the web security skills that are necessary.
Then, I was approaching the bug bounties like a pentest because
I was a pentester and I thought bug bounty is easy, but it wasn't.
With full time studies and part time work,
I also didn't have much time to do that.
And since I created the channel, it got even worse
and I didn't even want to spend my remaining time on bug bounty.
So even though I consider myself a great pentester and I have strong web
security skills, in bug bounty, I'm just a beginner,
just like many of you.
Now I want to spend roughly 50% of my time on content creation
and the other 50%
on bug bounty,
although so far I am not very good at maintaining this balance.
But anyway, I am finding some bugs
which is an absolutely amazing feeling.
And in this series,
I will show you my journey with exact numbers, time spent and so on.
Since my podcast with David Schutz,
I am focusing on the public bug bounty program
on Hackerone
without any recon - just focusing on understanding the application.
You can expect the next episode in about a month where I will show you
what were my results after 100 hours spent on that program.
Right now, I'm about at 60 hours.
And I won't to tell you, how exactly is it going but I will just tease
that I found a first bug after only two hours of hunting.
Make sure subscribe to the channel to not miss that episode.
And if you are a company that could benefit from advertising to IT
security audience
of about 15,000 unique visitors
per month, feel free to contact me at collab@bugbountyexplained.com
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye!